skilliq.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Statement and Disclosure Policy from SkillIQ

JoBookIt is committed to protecting the privacy of our users, and strives to provide a safe, secure user experience. This Privacy Policy sets forth the online data collection and usage policies and practices that apply to this web site. It does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. 

By clicking the “Accept” button during registration or by using this site, you explicitly accept, without limitation or qualification, of the collection, use and transfer of the personal information provided by you in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as it affects your rights and liabilities under law. If you disagree with the way we collect and process personal information collected on the web site, we recommend that you do not use it. 

## Scope of this Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to www.skilliq.com (the “Site”), which is owned by JoBookIt Technologies Ltd. (“JoBookIt”). It is JoBookIt’s policy to comply with data protection legislation. This regulates the processing of information relating to you and grants you various rights in respect of your personal data.

The Site contains links to other web sites over which we have no control. JoBookIt is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other web sites to which you choose to link from this site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other web sites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information.

## Information We Collect and Retain

We collect the following general types of information about you when you visit our Site: personal information, demographic information and behavioral information. Sometimes we collect combinations of all these types of information. In each case, it is indicated on the web site whether any personal or demographic data must be provided to use the requested service or not. 

Personal information is information that can be used to identify you, or any other individual to whom the information may relate, personally. We do not collect personal information unless you choose to provide it to us. Some examples of personal information that we collect in some areas of our Site, depending on the services you use and local law, are: 

  * Your name
  * Address
  * Email address 
  * Telephone number 
  * Credit card number 
  * Contact information 
  * Billing information 
  * Information about third parties, such as references or contacts, that you provide to us if you have their express written consent to do so. 

Demographic information is information that is not unique to you in the sense that it refers to selected population characteristics, such as your ZIP code or postal code, age, preferences, gender, race or ethnicity, occupation, career history, interests and favorites. 

We also collect behavioral information regarding how you use our site, the areas of our site that you visit, what services you access, and information about your computer hardware and software including your IP address, geolocation, browser and operating system type, domain names, access times and referring Web site. This information is necessary for analyzing the use of resources, troubleshooting problems, preventing fraud, and improving our services. 

## How Information is Used

We use the information we gather on the web site for the purposes of providing our services, responding to any queries you may have, operating and improving the web site, fostering a positive user experience and delivering the products and services that we offer to jobseekers and employers. Our services include the display of personalized products, content, and advertising relating to your career experience and interests. 

By registering to the site, by managing your profile, or expressly opting in when presented with choices, you have consented for us to use your information, subject to local law, in the following ways:

  * to allow you to create an account; 
  * to create a profile for you based on information that you have provided to us; 
  * to contact you about Site updates, informational and service-related communications, including important security updates; 
  * to provide you additional communications, information, and promotions such as newsletters and career advice; 
  * to inform you of other products or services available from JoBookIt or its affiliates (“Affiliates” means entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with JoBookIt Technologies Ltd.); 
  * to enable you to provide feedback, to contact us and for us to respond to you; 
  * to conduct surveys, questionnaires, promotions and contests, and to provide the results thereof such as success stories and contest winners; 
  * to provide information about you and your potential interest in job postings to employer customers; 
  * to provide products and services to employer customers to complete the recruitment and hiring process, such as accessing the [searchable resume] [Site’s ]database; 
  * to provide products and services that enable users to network, post information on bulletin boards, view and compare profiles, and career background and experience; 
  * to generate internal reports about the use of our site; 

Some of our products and services, such as our database and networking, enable third parties to see your personal information and to contact you. Profile information may be used for networking with other community members or may be visible to employers who are using the Site. 

Information provided by you will be accessed, used, and stored by others around the world, including countries that might not have legislation that guarantees adequate protection with respect to your country of residence. By providing your personal information for inclusion in our database, you acknowledge that you consent to your information being used as described here. While JoBookIT takes measures to safeguard your information from unauthorized access or inappropriate use by third parties, JoBookIT does not control these third parties and we are not responsible for their use of such information. 

## Disclosure of Information to Others

We disclose to third parties within your country and abroad your personal information, combined personal, demographic or behavioral information, as set forth below. 

1\. We may share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. We disclose information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include hosting our web servers, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies and individuals may be located in a country whose data protection legislation is different from your country, and they will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party or use that data for any other purpose.

2\. We supply your contact information to select third parties such as employers, recruiters, data aggregators, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you e-mail or otherwise communicating with you. We use data we have about you (such as the interests and preferences you have expressed) to determine whether you might be interested in the opportunities, products or services of a particular third party. 

We also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to the Site with JoBookIT’s clients, partners, other Site visitors, and other third parties so that they can understand the kinds of visitors to the Site and how those visitors use the Site. We may also aggregate on an anonymous basis data regarding job qualifications, schooling, age, experience level or other information relevant to the job search or competition among job seekers for any such job. Such data may be made available to employers or fellow job seekers or community members.

3\. We disclose information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith – after considering your privacy interests and other factors – that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. 

4\. We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of JoBookIT’s business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event JoBookIT becomes the subject of an insolvency proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, JoBookIT or its liquidator, administrator, receiver or administrative receiver may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the court. You will be notified of the sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party by email or through a prominent notice posted on the Site.

## An Important Note about Your Resume

When you create or post a resume to the Site, that resume is stored in our database.

All parties (including potential employers or others) with access to our database (or copies thereof) may have access to your resume and information. Employers or other parties with access to database may be located in countries whose data protection legislation may not be equivalent to the laws in your country. By giving us information, you are expressly consenting to such transfers of data occurring. Your information (including your resume) may be transferred to various potential employers, who may retain a copy of such information or distribute it to third parties, subject to local law. We cannot control their use and retention of your information.

We attempt to limit access to our database to legitimate users such as paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters and human resource professionals, as well as law enforcement and national security agencies, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to this database. We cannot control the use made of resumes or other information by third parties who access such resumes while they are in our database. You may make your resume unsearchable at any time; details of how to do this are given below. However, employers, recruiters and others who have paid for access to that database, as well as parties who have otherwise gained access to the database may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We cannot control the retention, use or privacy of resumes or profiles that have been downloaded by third parties. Accordingly, you should not put sensitive information, personality profiles, or other information you would not want made public, in your resume.

If you provide us with details of a reference, it is your responsibility to ensure that the person is aware that you have forwarded his/her details and has consented in writing for you to do so.

If you use our facilities to build a resume or to post a resume in our database, then you will be providing us with personal data we will use in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Your resume must not contain sensitive data relating to your (i) racial or ethnic origin (ii) political beliefs (iii) philosophical or religious beliefs (iv) membership of a trade union or political party (v) physical or mental health or genetic makeup, or (vi) addictions, sexual life (vii) the commission of criminal offences or proceedings and associated penalties or fines. If your resume does contain such data, then you agree that we may retain this information and use it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We cannot control third parties’ access to such information from our database.

## Your Choices About Your Information 

Because managing your career is a life-long process, we retain all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant until you change or make your personal data unsearchable as described below. You may have access to, review, correct, update and change your account profile information or resume at any time. Simply log into your account, go to your profile or resume, and make the necessary changes. You may request JoBookIt to make your resume unsearchable (i.e. employers or other parties will not have access to your resume or data) at any time by contacting us as provided below. Before providing you with a copy of your personal information or correcting, updating or making such information unsearchable, we reserve the right to verify and authenticate your identity and the personal information to which you have requested access. Access to or correction, updating or making of your personal information unsearchable may be denied or limited by JoBookIT if it would violate another person’s rights and/or as otherwise permitted by applicable law.

If you wish to make your account and information unsearchable, please contact us at Info@skilliq.com. An email will be sent to you to confirm that your personal information has been made inaccessible to employers or other parties. An archival copy which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet shall be retained only for as long as JoBookIT reasonably considers necessary for audit and record purposes. We will retain the information we gathered about you and keep an archival copy of this information in an anonymized form . If your personal information was previously accessed by others using our Site, we are not able to delete the information or copies thereof from their systems. If you wish to make your account and information searchable again, please contact us at Info@skilliq.com 

If you are a job seeker and have not logged onto the web site for an extended period, we may make your resume unsearchable.

If you previously opted to receive newsletters, commercial e-mails or other communications from JoBookIt or third parties, but subsequently change your mind, you may opt-out by editing your account profile as described above. If you previously opted not to receive such communications, you may later opt-in by editing your account profile.

## Important Information

### Security

You are responsible for ensuring that your log-in credentials (your username and password) are kept confidential.

JoBookIT has implemented technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. Notwithstanding such measures, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. Moreover, one of our primary purposes is to provide you with a platform to broadcast the information in your resume and profile widely and to maximize your career opportunities. Accordingly, such an environment does present a risk that unauthorized third parties will view this data. Further, your resume should not contain any sensitive data including personality profiles or data that you would not want made public. You should be aware that resumes you complete at your current place of work may be monitored by your current employer.

### Billing information 

Should you sign up for a premium features (as defined in the Terms of Use), we will require your billing information in order to process the transaction and to collect the fees involved.

We do not store your billing information, and this information will be discarded after your transaction has been processed. Nevertheless, the required information for your billing will be stored by our payment gateway company which will store your billing information on their secure payment gateway for as long as necessary to carry out the terms of your Premium account membership.

We may retain the last 4 digits of your credit card number, and credit card type, so that you may identify the card used in the future.

Should you cancel your Premium account membership, your billing information will be removed by the payment gateway company. 

Your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for your credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted. 

We also use cookies, web beacons, and Java Script to administer our site and deliver a personalized experience. For additional detailed information on each of these, please see below.

### Children

The Site is not intended for, nor do we knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13.

## Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and/or our Terms of Use at any time. Any and all changes and/or clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on this Site. You must refer to this Privacy Policy on an ongoing basis and preferably before each use of the website so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. 

## Legal and Contact Information

If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or believe that we have not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at Info@skilliq.com. You may also contact us by mail at 17 Ha Tidhar St. Rannana, Israel.

We will use reasonable efforts to answer promptly your question or resolve your problem. 

## Use of Cookies, Web Beacons, and Java Script 

Cookies: JobookIt uses "cookies" to help personalize and maximize your online experience and time online. A cookie is a text file that is either stored in your computer’s memory temporarily (a “session” cookie) or placed on your hard drive (a “persistent” cookie) by a Web page server. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to your computer and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

When you return to the Site, cookies enable us to retrieve the information you previously provided, so you can easily use the features that you customized. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster and more accurate results and a more personalized site experience

We also allow other companies to display advertisements to you while you are visiting our Site. Because your web browser must request these advertisements from the other companies’ servers, these companies can view, edit or set their own cookies, just as if you had requested a web page from their site. JoBookIt has no control over, and is not responsible for, the practices of those third party advertisers. Privacy Policy encourages you to review the policies of such advertisers. We use other third party ad servers as well; a way to opt out of third party cookies is to modify your browser settings to decline.

We allow persistent third party cookies as part of online advertising campaigns to determine and track site traffic landing from JobookIt’s advertising banners that have been placed on the websites of third parties. The data collected via these cookies is anonymous and the information is not linked to your personally identifiable information without your permission. The “persistent” cookies placed by our third party ad servers will remain on your computer after you have left our site for up to 20 years.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies at any time by modifying your browser settings. If you choose to decline cookies, however, that may hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on the web site.

*Web Beacons: JoBookIt Web pages may also contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Web beacons are not used to access your personally identifiable information on the Site; they are a technique we use to compile aggregated statistics about our web site usage. Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides.

Because Web beacons are the same as any other content request included in the recipe page, you cannot opt out or refuse them. However, they can be rendered ineffective by either opting out of cookies or changing the cookie setup in your browser.

JavaScript: JoBookIt also uses JavaScript, for example, within certain advertisements. JavaScript is a script language that enhances the functionality of websites, particularly in respect to pictures. We are not collecting any personal data via JavaScript but use it to inform employers about how many applicants have clicked on email addresses embedded in their job ads, for example. You may deactivate JavaScript via your browser settings or activate it the same way. If you disable JavaScript you will not be able to use some of the functions of the website.

Thank you for using the Site.
